No laws. No limits. One rule. Never fall in love.
Moulin Rouge! is a drama, romance, music film directed by Baz Luhrmann.
A celebration of love and creative inspiration takes place in the infamous, gaudy
and glamorous Parisian nightclub, at the cusp of the 20th century.
A young poet, who is plunged into the heady world of Moulin Rouge, begins a
passionate affair with the club's most notorious and beautiful star.
Christian, played by Ewan McGregor.
Satine, played by Nicole Kidman.
Toulouse-Lautrec, played by John Leguizamo.
Harold Zidler, played by Jim Broadbent.
The Duke, played by Richard Roxburgh.
The Doctor, played by Garry McDonald.
Moulin Rouge!
(, French: [mulɛ̃ ʁuʒ]) is a 2001 jukebox musical romantic drama film
directed, produced, and co-written by Baz Luhrmann.
It follows an English poet, Christian, who falls in love with the star of
the Moulin Rouge, cabaret actress and courtesan Satine.
The film uses the musical setting of the Montmartre Quarter of Paris and is the final part of
Luhrmann's Red Curtain Trilogy, following Strictly Ballroom (1992) and Romeo + Juliet (1996).
A co-production of Australia and the United States, it features an ensemble cast starring Nicole Kidman and Ewan McGregor,
with Jim Broadbent, Richard Roxburgh, John Leguizamo, Jacek Koman, and Caroline O'Connor in supporting roles.
Moulin Rouge!
premiered at the 2001 Cannes Film Festival, where it competed for the Palme d'Or and was
released in theaters on 25 May 2001 in Australia and on 1 June 2001 in North America.
The film was praised for Luhrmann's direction, the performances of the
cast, its soundtrack, costume design, and production values.
It was also a commercial success, grossing $179.2
million on a $50 million budget.
At the 74th Academy Awards, the film received eight nominations, including Best
Picture, and won two (Best Production Design and Best Costume Design).
Later critical reception for Moulin Rouge!
remained positive and has been considered by many to be one of the best films of all time, with it
ranking 53rd in the BBC's 2016 poll of the 100 greatest films of the 21st century.
A stage musical adaptation premiered in 2018.
The film explores themes of paris, france, nightclub, fairy, courtesan, duke.
The tone is emotional.